let's look at the solution to our not
most recently used replacement policy
quiz
we have these accesses and now let's see
which ones might be hits
and which ones might be misses
this one is definitely a miss because we
have nothing in the cache so now we have
brought a into the cache
this one is definitely a hit
now we're gonna access b
and this is definitely a miss and we're
gonna put b in a separate place in the
cache from where we put a because a is
the most recently used block so we will
put b
in one of the other three blocks and we
definitely will put b
in a line that doesn't contain a so we
will not kick out a because a is the
most recently used block
we will choose one of the other
three lines to evict to put b there so
so far if this is our cache we have a
and b there now we will access a and
have a hit so c is definitely a miss and
at that point a is the most recently
used block and we will find one of these
three to evict to put c there
in this type of a situation it looks
like b might actually be evicted but
remember that we also have valid bits
for all these blocks so when we have a
replacement policy typically
we will first fill all the lines in the
cash set before we move on and
start evicting something so we will put
c into one of the empty slots and now
that is the most recently accessed line
a
is now a hit and
that is now the most recently accessed
line
now when we access d it's not in the
cache
so we will have a miss
we will again put the in an unused place
and that will now be the most recently
used one then a gets accessed and we
have a hit and at this point a is the
most recently used block now we will
have a miss on e because it's not in the
cache and now the question is what will
be evicted we will definitely not evict
a
so we know
that the next four accesses to a will be
all hits e will be replacing one of
these three blocks
so if we replace c or d then here we
will have a hit if we however select b
for replacement and put e there then b
here will have a miss so we have a hit
or a miss here in total we have one two
three four five or six
misses so this is the final answer to
this quiz